Guide to the William L. Taylor papers, 1954-2009 MS2287
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Speeches and testimony, 1959-2009; Series 1; 9 Linear Feet
  - Congressional hearing, Chicago, IL, 2006 August 28; Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Shepherd Park authors, 2006 September 13; Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - LCCR Executive Committee meeting, 2006 September 27; Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - National Journal Policy Council, 2006 September 28; Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - LCCR Board meeting, 2006 September 29; Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - New York Times profile, 2006 January; Series 1 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Georgetown University Law Center mock trial, 2006; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - U.S. Department of Education growth models, 2006 October 16; Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Texas Book Festival, 2006 October 29; Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Chapter on Title IV and comments, 2006 November; Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Columbia Teachers College Symposium on Educational Equity, 2006 November 14; Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Roundtable on NCLB, University of California Washington Center, 2006 November 16; Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - LCCR National Board Meeting, 2006 December 06; Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Cleveland Conference, 2006 December 07; Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Mishkan Torah, 2007 January 12; Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - American Bar Association mid-year meeting, 2006 February 09; Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - University of Massachusetts, 2006 April 10; Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - American Educational Research Association, San Diego, 2007 April 15; Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Papers for Brookings Institution, fiscal equality, 2007 April 30; Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Notes for American Bar Association speech, 2007 August 11; Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Testimony, House of Representatives NCLB Reauthorization, 2007 September; Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - The National Academies, Workshop on Multiple Measures, 2007 November 16; Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Talk with students from Columbia Teachers College, 2008 January 09; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - ACS, CBOCS, 2008 February 12; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - National Academy of Education Annual Meeting, 2008 October 17; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Seminar on the Practice and Theory of Shangshu for Public Interest, Beijing, China, 2008 November 01; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Harvard Interdistrict Conference, 2009 January 16; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Taylor speeches: LCCR Humphrey Award and Brooklyn College Commencement, 2001; Series 1 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Oral history -- Brooklyn College, 2001; Series 1 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Oral history -- Olson, 2005; Series 1 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Oral history -- Daniel, 2006; Series 1 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Oral history -- Miller, 2007; Series 1 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - W.L. Taylor -- Transcript of Interview by the Civil Rights Documentation Project (John H. Britton), undated; Series 1 (Box 100, Folder 12)
  - Oral histories, 1967-1995; Series 1 (Box 100, Folder 13)
  - Eulogies for Alice Rosen, 2003; Series 1 (Box 105, Folder 5)
  - State of Education in the U.S., 2007; Series 1 (Box 105, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1958-2008; Series 2; 6.5 Linear Feet
  This series contains incoming and outgoing correspondence of William L. Taylor from 1958 to 2008, including official correspondence he sent and received at the U.S. Commission on Civil Rights as well as correspondence he sent and received as a leader of the Center for National Policy Review, Citizens' Commission on Civil Rights, the Leadership Conference on Civil Rights, and the Leadership Conference Education Fund.
  - Correspondence, 1954; Series 2 (Box 98, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1955; Series 2 (Box 109, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence -- personal, 1958-1968; Series 2 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1960; Series 2 (Box 108, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence -- personal, 1963-1971; Series 2 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1964-1965; Series 2 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence -- congratulatory letters on appointment as Staff Director, CCR, 1965; Series 2 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Invtitations, 1965-1968; Series 2 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1967; Series 2 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1966-1968; Series 2 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1968-1969; Series 2 (Box 108, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1968; Series 2 (Box 109, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence on resignation, 1968; Series 2 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1968-1969; Series 2 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence -- U.S. Commission on Civil Rights, 1969; Series 2 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1971; Series 2 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1972; Series 2 (Box 98, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence -- CNPR, 1973-1983; Series 2 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1977-80; Series 2 (Box 99, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1979; Series 2 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1982; Series 2 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1981; Series 2 (Box 99, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1982; Series 2 (Box 99, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1983; Series 2 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1983; Series 2 (Box 99, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1983; Series 2 (Box 98, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1983-1986; Series 2 (Box 98, Folder 4)
  - LCCR incoming correspondence, 1999 October; Series 2 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - LCEF incoming correspondence, 1999 October; Series 2 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - LCEF outgoing correspondence, 1999 October; Series 2 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - LCCR outgoing correspondence, 1999 October; Series 2 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1998-2001; Series 2 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - White House invitation, 1993; Series 2 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - CCCR correspondence, 1994 March-June; Series 2 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - CCCR correspondence, 1994 July-December; Series 2 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - CCCR individual case and litigation request replies, 1994; Series 2 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Crank letters, 1995; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - CCCR correspondence, 1995 January-June; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - CCCR individual case and litigation request replies, 1995; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Requests for information, 1994-1995; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1994-2008; Series 2 (Box 98, Folder 5)
  - CCCR correspondence, 1995 July-September; Series 2 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - CCCR correspondence, 1995 October-December; Series 2 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - CCCR correspondence, 1996 January-March; Series 2 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - CCCR correspondence, 1996 April-May; Series 2 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - CCCR correspondence, 1996 June-August; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - CCCR correspondence, 1996 September-December; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1999 January; Series 2 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1999 February; Series 2 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1999 March; Series 2 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1999 April; Series 2 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1999 May; Series 2 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1999 June; Series 2 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1999 August; Series 2 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1999 September; Series 2 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence Title I, 1999 September; Series 2 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1999 October; Series 2 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1999 October; Series 2 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1999 November; Series 2 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1999 December; Series 2 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - CCCR General Info, 1999; Series 2 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 2002 January; Series 2 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 2002 February; Series 2 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 2002 March; Series 2 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 2002 April; Series 2 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 2002 May; Series 2 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 2002 June; Series 2 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 2002 July; Series 2 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 2002 August; Series 2 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 2002 September; Series 2 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 2002 October; Series 2 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 2002 November; Series 2 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 2002 December; Series 2 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 2003 January; Series 2 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 2003 February; Series 2 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 2003 March; Series 2 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 2003 April; Series 2 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 2003 May; Series 2 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 2003 June; Series 2 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 2003 July; Series 2 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 2003 August; Series 2 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 2003 September; Series 2 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 2003 October; Series 2 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 2003 November; Series 2 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 2003 December; Series 2 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 2004 January; Series 2 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 2004 February; Series 2 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 2004 March; Series 2 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 2004 April; Series 2 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 2004 May; Series 2 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 2004 June; Series 2 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 2004 July; Series 2 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 2004 August; Series 2 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 2004 September; Series 2 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 2004 October; Series 2 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 2004 November; Series 2 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 2004 December; Series 2 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 2005 January-February; Series 2 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 2005 March-May; Series 2 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 2005 June-August; Series 2 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 2005 September-October; Series 2 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 2006 January-May; Series 2 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 2006 June-December; Series 2 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 2007 January-March; Series 2 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 2007 April-December; Series 2 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 2004-2007; Series 2 (Box 99, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 2008; Series 2 (Box 30, Folder 5)
- Subject files, 1954-2003; Series 3; 24.5 Linear Feet
  Arranged in eight subseries according to stages in Taylor's career: 1. NAACP; 2. U.S. Commission on Civil Rights; 3. Yale Law School; 4. Center for National Policy Review; 5. Citizens' Commission on Civil Rights; 6. Leadership Conference on Civil Rights; 7. Liddell v. Board of Education of the City of St. Louis; and 8. General.
  Within each subseries, the material is arranged alphabetically.
  The material in this series, dating from 1954 to 2003, includes studies, reports, legislation, notes, correspondence, teaching materials, legal documents, press releases, and statistical data documenting Taylor's legal advocacy work in the following organizations: the NAACP, the U.S. Commission on Civil Rights, Yale Law School, the Center for National Policy Review, the Citizens' Commission on Civil Rights, the Leadership Conference on Civil Rights, and Taylor's own private law practice. Files focus primarily on legal and legislative efforts to achieve racial integration in schools, with some additional material on combating racial discrimination in employment, housing, and voting.
  - NAACP, Series 3 Subseries 1
    - NAACP cases -- Arkansas and Virginia, Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - NAACP judgments, 1954-1955; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - NAACP memos, 1955-1956; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - NAACP pleadings, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - NAACP sociological material, magazine articles, 1954; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - NAACP speeches, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - U.S. Commission on Civil Rights, Series 3 Subseries 2
    - Minutes, Commission meetings prior to 1965, 1964; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 100, Folder 1)
    - Minutes -- Commission meetings, 1965-1966; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Minutes -- Commission meetings, 1967-1968; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - 1968 budget, 1967; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Summary of meeting on Commission program, 1968 July 26; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - 96th Commission meeting, 1968 September 5; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Alabama hearing outline and follow-up, 1968; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Cleveland, 1967; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Commissioners, 1965-1967; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - DC schools, 1968; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - HUD and Labor, 1967; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Education, undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Education -- Decentralization, undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Education -- Litigation, undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Education material, undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Equal Opportunity in Federally Assisted Programs [conference], 1964; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - FEB Progress Report #1, Oakland Task Force -- San Francisco FEB, 1967 November 10; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Follow-up to Kerner Commission Report -- Downs' Paper, undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Food, undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Future Commission Program, 1969-, 1968; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Housing, 1968; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Land contracts and tenant unions, undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Life insurance industry -- Billion dollar program for inner city, undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Memo -- "Chicago Power Structure", undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Migrant workers (Housing and Labor), undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Minority contractors, 1968; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Negro contractors, undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Palm Beach, Florida, incident involving British West Indian Farm Workers, undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - Proposed Civil Rights Act of 1966, undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - Racial statistics, undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - School Integration Still Makes Sense, 1967; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - Speeches, William L. Taylor -- Civil disobedience speech delivered before NCLCH -- "Some Observations on the Strategies of Protest", 1964 March 20; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - SD [Staff Director]/Agenda item -- Santiestevan, Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - SD [Staff Director]/Mississippi -- Interim Report of Commission and related correspondence with Attorney General and President, 1963; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - SD [Staff Director]/Papers and articles -- Harris Wofford, undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - SD [Staff Director]/Poor People's Campaign -- (Response to the demands), undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - SD [Staff Director's] reading material -- education, undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - SD [Staff Director's] reading material -- employment, undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - SD [Staff Director's] reading material -- The Ghettoes, undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - SD [Staff Director's] reading material -- housing, undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - SD [Staff Director's] reading material -- legal [1 of 2], undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - SD [Staff Director's] reading material -- legal [2 of 2], undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - SD [Staff Director's] Urban Problems (background material), undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Task Force on Civil Rights, 1966-1967; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Task Force on Civil Rights, 1968; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Tax Exemption and Tax Deductibility for Segregated Private Schools Under the Internal Revenue Code of 1954/Legal, Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Technical Information Center Catalog and Dual Dictionary [U.S. Commission on Civil Rights], 1966; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Title VI -- Agriculture and DOD, undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - WH/KA background -- E.O. 11063 "Equal Opportunity in Housing", 1962 November 20; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - White House conference follow-up, undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - WLT [William L. Taylor]/Personal -- confirmation material, undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - WLT [William L. Taylor]/Personal -- personnel actions, undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Papers re: Glickstein appointment, undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - WLT [William L. Taylor]/Personal -- biographical data, undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Mr. Taylor's miscellaneous handwritten notes, undated; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Report of State Advisory Commissions of the USCCR, 1965; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 94, Folder 1)
    - Report of State Advisory Commissions of the USCCR [1 of 2], 1966; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 94, Folder 2)
    - Report of State Advisory Commissions of the USCCR [2 of 2], 1966; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 93, Folder 1)
    - Report of State Advisory Commissions of the USCCR [1 of 2], 1967; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 93, Folder 2)
    - Report of State Advisory Commissions of the USCCR [2 of 2], 1967; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 93, Folder 3)
    - Report of State Advisory Commissions of the USCCR [1 of 2], 1968; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 93, Folder 4)
    - Report of State Advisory Commissions of the USCCR [2 of 2], 1968; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 93, Folder 5)
    - Report of State Advisory Commissions of the USCCR, 1969; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 93, Folder 6)
    - National Civil Liberties Clearinghouse Conference, 21 March 1969; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 100, Folder 2)
    - USCCR appointment book, 1969; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 109, Folder 7)
  - Yale Law School, Series 3 Subseries 3
    - Course at Jonathan Edwards, undated; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - Ford Foundation and Yale Law School fellowship, 1968-1969; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - Housing Research Project -- Yale Law School, undated; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - Lawyers' Committee for Civil Rights Under Law, 1968; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - Law schools, 1969-1970; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - Simon Pub Education course, 1970; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Notes for Jonathan Edwards/Yale course, 1969-1970; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 108, Folder 11)
  - Center for National Policy Review, Series 3 Subseries 4
    - Affirmative action, 1976-1984; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Board of Education v. Califano, 1978; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Bonnie's Adams report, 1979; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Breaking Down Barriers -- Pearce, 1980; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Catholic University Law School search for dean, 1976-1977; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Center, 1970-1972; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Center and University relationship, undated; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Center planning, 1975; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Center for National Policy Review sign, undated; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 112, Folder 1)
    - CNPR-Catholic University fight, 1985; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Current Working -- Common Cause, Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Desegregation and Black Achievement: A Review of the Research, 1983; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Education -- 504 Regs/HEW, 1977; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Education -- HEW/OMB data collection, 1976; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Education -- HEW/schools/housing, undated; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Education -- letters to the editor, undated; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Education -- Model Integrated School, undated; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Education -- "School Segregation in the North..." by Paul Dimond, Harvard Law Review, undated; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Education -- Section 504, undated; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Education -- South Carolina Suspension Policy, undated; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Education -- Weinstein, Jack, undated; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Education -- WLT [William L. Taylor's] testimony, House Judiciary/Civil Rights Enforcement at DOEd, undated; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Emergency School Aid Act, 1978; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - Feminization of Poverty, 1983; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Ford Foundation book project correspondence and notes, 1973; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Ford Foundation -- future of Center, undated; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Ford proposals -- Center's beginning, 1969-1970; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - General Center pro-bono reports, undated; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - GRS-A Perspective of Community and Public Interest Groups, Pablo Eisenberg, 1973 December 5; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Pearce, Diana -- articles, 1981-1982; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Remarks on Metropolitan School Integration, 1972; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - School desegregation -- Effect of School Desegregation on Placement in Special Education Programs/Loewen, 1980; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - School desegregation -- Impact of Mandatory/Voluntary Desegregation in Large School Districts, 1981; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - School desegregation -- Informal Hearings on Urban Desegregation, 1977; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - School desegregation -- Metro-wide Desegregation and Other Desegregation Papers, undated; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - School desegregation -- National Association of Counties Speech on Metro School Integration, undated; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - School desegregation -- Newspaper articles: "Growth, Complexities and Attitudes of Suburban Americans", undated; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - School desegregation -- "Recovering Counsel Fees in School Desegregation Cases" (Chachkin), undated; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - School desegregation -- Resegregation Study, undated; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - School desegregation -- School Integration Cases Involving Claims for Metropolitan Relief, undated; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - School desegregation -- State Liability, undated; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 49, Folder 10)